立法會主席。
發現。
石禮謙議員就政府賬目委員會第五十九號報告書向本會發言，石禮謙。
多謝，Mr. President。
On behalf of the Public Accounts Committee, namely PAC, I have the honour to table our report number 59 today. This report contains three main parts.
A， the committee's assessment of the actions taken by the administration in response to our recommendation made in previous PAC reports number 56 and 57。
B. The observations of the committee on the report of director of audit on the accounts of the government for the year ended 31st March 2012, and finally the conclusions reached by the committee on the director of audit's report number 59.
On the results of value for money audits completed between March and September 2012, and tabled in this council on 14 November 2012.
pursuant to discussion by the committee, we decided to study in detail four chapters covered by the audit report number 59, which in our views contain more serious allegations of irregularities or shortcomings.
Our approach, as always, has been fact-finding and problem-solving, rather than simply assigning blame and expressing opinions.
我 wish to emphasise that the objective of the whole exercise is to maintain and improve the high standards of accountability which the administration has attained, and to learn from past lessons in order to ensure that public monies have been spent with due regard to economy, efficiency.
和effectiveness。
In this spirit, I wish to draw the attention of this council to several subjects and highlight the need for further accountability, transparency and prudence in the management of public resources.
主席，第一，我講要講土地補貼給私人醫院。委員會大為震驚，雖然這一直是公眾政策，即非營利的私人醫院會被給予土地，以零或名義的補貼作為回報。
兩條要件：首先，提供免費或低收費病牀；第二，從任何醫院的營業盈餘中撥回利潤，以改善和擴大設施。這兩條要件被省略了，從部分直接撥款中。
嗯。
Given that private hospital nowadays do make profits and land in Hong Kong is scarce and very precious, the committee considers that the administration needs to ensure that private hospital have been making proper use of the sites granted to them, including benefiting a wider section of the public.
係。
第二個主題，我將簡要提及，是土地賣售給私人醫院發展。
The committee is again dismayed and find it inexcusable that there has been over provision of land for the development of a private hospital in new territories.
such overprovision resulted not only in the surplus land having left idle for years, but also gave the owner an unfair and unjustified advantage over other developers on re-selling the land for residential development at the premium to be paid.
行政已經向委員會保證，類似事故不會再發生。第一，行政將會更加精確地決定醫院的規模，以及評估服務擴張的需求。第二，嚴格的發展控制將會。
被 stipulated in land grants of government sites for new private hospital, such as land use, total gross floor area and maximum site coverage and building heights.
Thirdly, I would wish to reflect the committee's concern about the regulatory control of private hospital.
委員會 finds it again unacceptable that the administration had not always taken effective regulatory actions against private hospital.
一checklist was not used for inspection on private hospital in 2009 and 2012. According to the established guidelines, regulatory letters should be issued to private hospitals if serious irregularities are detected in inspections or investigation of.
世紀事件和批評。
但，的 issuance of such letters to private hospitals was sadly few. Furthermore, the administration did not refer cases involving suspected professional misconduct of doctors or nurses to the relevant professional bodies for follow up.
委員會亦都 dismayed by the administration.
Only issued three press releases relating to centennial events of private hospital from 2007 to 2011.
醫院管理局會考慮披露一個紀念事件，如果。
event has immediate major impact on the public or involve a patient's death.
However, the administration would only consider disclosing a sentinel event in private hospital if such event had major impact on public healthcare system, or if it constituted a persistent public health risk or involved a large number of patients.
委員會敦促行政局對準確披露紀念事件的標準作出調整，以確保在私營和公立醫院中均能準確披露。
To better safeguard public health, the committee hopes that the steering committee on review of the regulation of private healthcare facilities set up by the government in October last year to review the regulatory regime on private healthcare facilities, including private hospitals.
會 come up with more effective measures within the year.
我 now turn to the committee's deliberations on the two chapters on air pollution.
The committee is disappointed and dissatisfied about the little progress made by the administration in tackling air pollution over the years. The committee is very concerned about the adverse health effects on air pollution.
委員會是強烈認為，政府開支應該更好地花在預防措施上，以保護公眾健康。
by improving air quality, than on medical costs arising from curing health problems associated with air pollution.
委員會 welcomes the commitment of the administration.
To work in a concerted manner to proactively improve air quality and carefully consider public health when formulating clean air policy.
委員會預期，行政會從過去的經驗中學習，在制定新措施以減少來自車輛、海船和發電廠，以及湄公河三角洲地區的排放。
在採用一 carrot and stick 接近，一右平衡，between incentives and disincentives， must be struck， to ensure the effectiveness of these measures and prudent use of public money。
委員會預期行政會soon宣佈其目標，與里程碑，以推動新空氣質目標的逐步達成，這些目標將於2014年生效。
The committee look forward to receiving an update from the administration on its action plan, in respect of the revamp of the air pollution index reporting system to enhance public awareness of air pollution. Mr. President, before I conclude, I wish to record my appreciation and contribution.
Made by members of the PAC, particularly the two lead members, namely the Honourable Ellen Leung and the Honourable Kenneth Leung. Our gratitude also goes to the representatives of the administration who attended the hearings, helped by PAC.
I would also like to express our gratitude to the Director of Audit and his colleagues for their unfailing support, and lastly but not least, to the Legal Secretariat for their great support. Thank you, Mr. President.
質詢。